Michael Wassell

31 Roxby Avenue, Guisborough, TS14 8LF

Email: mike1791.mw@googlemail.com

Mobile: 07816326396

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/michael-wassell-60a763a8

GitHub: https://github.com/M-Wassell

Summary:

Currently working as a Technical Account Manager at razorblue, I'm a career changer from the Royal Navy, with experience of working in dangerous and demanding circumstances where teamwork and integrity were paramount. Prior to working as a Technical Account Manager, I worked at The Verve Group as a Junior Software Developer, here I worked with frontend technologies such as JavaScript, React, HTML and CSS, as well as DevOps/Git to manage version control and launch new versions on the inhouse software. Backend development was done using C# with SQL database. Software development is something I continue to do in my own time, as it's something I'm very passionate about.

Skills:

- Javascript, C#, HTML, CSS
- Git, Git Bash CLI
- SQL, Jest
- Agile working
- VS Code, VS 2019
- TDD

- Managerial/ Supervisory Experience
- Communication/Team player
- Problem solver/Integrity
- Time Management/ Project Management
- Microsoft 365 Desktop apps
- Research

Employment History:

Razorblue

Jan 2022 - Current

Technical Account Manager

- Creating, nurturing and maintaining long-lasting customer and colleague relationships by thoroughly researching and understanding the client and their objectives
- Taking ownership of all customer needs to ensure the best outcomes for my client
- Transforming my customer's functional requirements into technical proposals via discussion, documentation and close-working with business owners and internal team members to ensure my customer has the right solution and the best experience
- Acting as a de facto IT manager for my customers by developing robust IT strategy documents and planning their technology roadmap
- Identify and nurture new opportunities around the use of technology and services
- Act as the commercial resource for my customers, ensuring orders are identified, raised and processed appropriately to requirements

The Verve Group Junior Software Developer

July 2021 - Jan 2022

- Participate in agile meetings including stand-ups, planning sessions, and retrospectives, contributing to team discussions, providing updates on progress, and actively participating in the decision-making process.
- Use Azure Boards to manage workflow, track tasks, and produce development documentation, ensuring transparency and efficient collaboration within the team.
- Investigate and implement bug fixes, demonstrating problem-solving skills and a commitment to improving product quality and user experience.
- Participate in code reviews with my peers, providing constructive feedback and learning from others to improve coding practices and maintain high-quality codebase.
- Use Source-Tree in conjunction with DevOps and Git to ensure version control compliance, maintaining code integrity and facilitating effective team collaboration.

- Implement changes within the current system using JavaScript, adhering to acceptance criteria to ensure correct implementation and alignment with project requirements.
- Make visual changes to the software using HTML and CSS where applicable, enhancing user interface and improving user experience.
- Make changes in C# to the backend code ensuring the correct functionality is applied, demonstrating proficiency in the language and attention to detail in delivering accurate solutions.
- Ensure ticket scoping is kept to a minimum by creating a new ticket for separate issues, promoting efficient task management and preventing scope creep.
- Research ahead of the current sprint to understand any new technologies, demonstrating initiative and a commitment to continuous learning.
- Attend North Coders bootcamp to progressively grow my knowledge and understanding in JavaScript full stack development, showing dedication to professional development and mastery of new skills.

Home Fix Computers

Jun 2020 - Sept 2020

Customer Service/ IT Help desk representative

- Provide customers with IT support in person, over the phone or via email.
- Ensure customers were given accurate and up to date information regarding their software and hardware issues.

JB Skills Training

Jan 2017 - June 2018

IT and Social Media Assessor

• Deliver Apprenticeship frameworks in Social Media for a business level 3, IT level 2/3 and customer service level 2, including embedding Functional Skills in Maths, English and ICT to learners in the workplace through a holistic teaching and assessment methods.

Pirtek Jan 2016 - Jan 2017

CR Manager/ Social Media Marketing

- Run social media marketing campaigns using multiple platforms, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram.
- Research and keep up to date with current trends and changes to social media platforms.

Royal Navy

May 2011 - Mar 2015

Mine Warfare Specialist

- Launch, retrieve and maintain the Sea Fox (mini submersible used to detect and destroy mines)
- Test, maintain and fault find on fibre optic cable, used in conjunction with the Sea Fox.

Education/ Qualifications:

Teesside University

Sept 2018 – June 2021

Computer Science BSc

Modules include: Systems design and databases, Algorithms and data Structures, Java/ Applications, Internet Architecture and Security, Advanced Java Programming, Relational and NoSQL Database, Al Programming, Internet of Things, Software Reliability, DevOps, Android Application Development.

Middlesbrough College

BTEC in Sports & Exercise Science

Billingham Campus School

10 GCSEs achieved including C grades and above in Maths, English and Science.

Further Training/ Qualifications:

Driving Licence(Clean)

Technical Sales Apprenticeship Level 3
Mental Health First Aid
Information Advice and Guidance Level 2
IT Professional Extended Diploma Level 3 (QCF)
Certificate in Assessing Vocational Achievement (QCF) Level 3
Oct 2017

Hobbies/Interests:

I have a keen interest in staying up-to-date with the latest technology changes and developments in software. In my free time, I enjoy socialising with family and friends, as well as staying active through activities such as walking and running. As part of my own personal development, I've invested in Udemy courses labelled "The Complete Web Development Bootcamp" and "Learn C# By Building Applications". The course content is thorough and robust, covering topics in depth such as C#, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, JQuery, DOM, React.js and more.

References:

References are available on request.